Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听 EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是 Marco。
My name is Kathryn and today we're going to be helping you find someone to help out around
我是 Kathryn，今天我们要帮你找个人来帮忙处理
the house.
家务活。
That's right.
没错。
So we're looking for someone to help us do some things around the house.
所以我们正在找人帮我们做些家务事。
So we're going to talk about this more in depth.
我们会更深入地讨论这个话题。
But first, let's take a look at one word on vocabulary preview.
但首先，让我们先看一下词汇预览中的一个词。
Vocabulary preview.
词汇预览。
So the beginning of today's dialogue has to do with a newspaper ad.
今天对话的开头是关于一则报纸广告。
We are writing an ad for the newspaper.
我们正在为报纸写一则广告。
Now what exactly is a newspaper ad, Marco?
那么，Marco，报纸广告到底是什么呢？
That's right.
没错。
So in the newspapers, usually there is a section called the classifieds where people post ads
在报纸上，通常有一个叫分类广告的板块，人们在那里发布广告
or advertisements or adverts where maybe they're selling their car or they're looking to hire
或广告，可能是卖车，或者招聘
people.
人员。
So this is what a newspaper ad is.
这就是报纸广告。
You're selling something, you're buying something or maybe you want to hire people, etc.
你在卖东西、买东西，或者想雇人等等。
It is basically an advertisement in the newspaper to find help.
它基本上就是报纸上用来找帮手的广告。
All right.
好的。
So let's listen to our dialogue and when we come back, we'll be talking more about the
那么让我们听一下对话，等我们回来时，会进一步讨论你听到的
words and phrases you've heard.
单词和短语。
Can you help me write a newspaper ad?
你能帮我写一则报纸广告吗？
Sure.
当然。
What are you looking to buy or sell?
你想买或卖什么？
Actually, I want to hire someone to help me around the house.
其实，我想雇个人帮我做家务。
Oh, you want to get a maid?
哦，你想找个女佣？
Well, I think it's better if you call her a cleaning lady or domestic help.
嗯，我觉得你最好称她为清洁女工或家政帮手。
Okay.
好的。
So what do you want her to do?
那你希望她做什么？
Well, let's see.
嗯，让我想想。
I want her to come in three times a week for a couple of hours to clean the kitchen, bathroom
我希望她每周来三次，每次几个小时，打扫厨房、浴室，
and maybe do some cooking.
也许再做点饭。
Got it.
明白了。
And how much do you offer per month?
那你每月出多少钱？
I would pay her hourly.
我会按小时付钱。
I don't know what the going rate is though.
不过我不知道现在的行情是多少。
I know for sure it's more than minimum wage, but maybe you should just negotiate with the
我肯定这比最低工资高，但也许你应该和回应广告的人
person that answers the ad.
协商一下。
Great.
太好了。
I'll try to help.
我会尽力帮忙。
All right, we're back.
好的，我们回来了。
So now let's take a look at language takeaway.
现在让我们看一下语言要点。
Language takeaway.
语言要点。
Okay.
好的。
So first of all today, Marco, the advertisement is about wanting to hire someone.
首先，Marco，这则广告是关于想雇人。
Now, this is an important verb, especially when we're trying to find help.
这是一个重要的动词，尤其是当我们想找帮手时。
The verb to hire.
动词“hire”。
That's right.
没错。
So to hire means to give someone work, to offer a contract to someone.
“Hire”意思是给某人工作，向某人提供合同。
Okay.
好的。
So my boss hired me three years ago.
所以我的老板三年前雇了我。
That means he gave me a job three years ago.
这意味着他三年前给了我一份工作。
That's right.
没错。
But this is not just for office jobs.
但这不仅限于办公室工作。
This is for all kinds of jobs.
这适用于各种工作。
So what about cutting your grass or doing your lawn?
那比如修剪草坪或打理花园呢？
That's right.
没错。
So you can hire a gardener, for example, and it's basically the same thing.
所以你可以雇一个园丁，例如，基本上是一样的。
It means that you're going to pay someone to work for you.
这意味着你要付钱让别人为你工作。
Okay.
好的。
So let's say you wanted to hire a maid, M-A-I-D, a maid.
假设你想雇一个女佣，M-A-I-D，女佣。
But this is a little bit old fashioned, this word.
但这个词有点过时了。
What does a maid do or what did a maid do?
女佣做什么，或者以前女佣做什么？
Well, a maid is basically a woman, a female servant, so to say, a person that basically
嗯，女佣基本上是一个女人，一个女仆，可以说，一个为你
serves you.
服务的人。
All right.
好的。
So she cleans the house.
所以她打扫房子。
She maybe puts the covers on the beds, washes the dishes, cooks, does all of these domestic
她可能铺床、洗碗、做饭，做所有这些家务
things.
事。
So she works around the house.
所以她在家务活上工作。
But because there's a bad association, we don't like to think, oh, we have servants.
但因为有些不好的联想，我们不喜欢想，哦，我们有仆人。
We don't say maid anymore.
我们不再说“maid”了。
We have two other ways of saying this word.
我们有两种其他方式来说这个词。
That's right.
没错。
So we could say that we want to hire a cleaning lady, right?
所以我们可以说想雇一个清洁女工，对吧？
Or we want to hire domestic help.
或者想雇家政帮手。
Okay.
好的。
Now there's an important difference between these two words.
这两个词之间有一个重要的区别。
First of all, cleaning lady is a woman, a lady, and she is someone who only cleans.
首先，清洁女工是一个女人，一位女士，她只负责清洁。
She doesn't take care of your children.
她不照看你的孩子。
She doesn't walk your dogs.
她不遛你的狗。
She basically just cleans the house, washes the dishes, cleans the clothes, washes the
她基本上只是打扫房子、洗碗、洗衣服、洗
floors.
地板。
So she's a cleaning lady.
所以她是个清洁女工。
Now domestic help, this is a little bit more general.
而“domestic help”（家政帮手）这个说法更宽泛一些。
Right.
对。
So domestic help would be a little bit more in depth of what the person's going to do.
所以“domestic help”会更深入地描述这个人要做的事情。
So we'll help with the domestic work, with domestic meaning the house.
所以我们说帮忙做家务，“domestic”指的是房子。
So this person will maybe cook for you, clean the house, take care of the kids, do everything
所以这个人可能会为你做饭、打扫房子、照看孩子，做所有
that is associated with the house.
与房子相关的事情。
So it's important to see that domestic means something that has to do with the house.
所以重要的是要明白“domestic”指的是与房子有关的事情。
This is help man or woman in the house.
这是指家里的帮手，可以是男是女。
Right.
对。
All right.
好的。
So that's all we have for language takeaway, but we do have another section, Fluency Builder,
这就是我们“语言要点”部分的内容，但我们还有另一个部分，“流利度提升”，
in which we're going to look at some great words and phrases.
我们会在那里看一些很棒的单词和短语。
Fluency Builder.
流利度提升。
All right.
好的。
So first on Fluency Builder, let's take a look at how we're going to pay the person
首先在“流利度提升”中，我们来看看如何支付这个人报酬，
because obviously we were saying that we want to hire this person.
因为显然我们之前说想雇佣这个人。
We're going to pay them.
我们要付钱给他们。
So how are we going to pay them?
那我们怎么付钱呢？
The person said, I would pay the woman her hourly.
那个人说，我会按小时付给这个女人。
I would pay her hourly.
我会按小时付给她。
Okay.
好的。
So this is the rate.
这就是费率。
This is how much she will be paid.
这就是她要被支付的金额。
And we don't say she will be paid $10,000 per year.
我们不会说她每年挣一万美元。
We say she'll be paid $10 per hour.
我们会说她每小时挣十美元。
So we pay per hour.
所以我们按小时支付。
This is paying her hourly.
这就是按小时付给她。
Right.
对。
So if you have an hourly wage, that means that you get paid per hour.
所以如果你有“hourly wage”（时薪），那就意味着你按小时拿钱。
In contrast with a salary, that means that you would get a fixed amount every month.
与“salary”（月薪）相对，那意味着你每个月拿固定金额。
All right.
好的。
So if the monthly salary is $1,000, for example, you could break that down and say, but every
所以如果月薪是一千美元，举个例子，你可以分解开来说，但每天
day you earn 100.
你挣一百。
You work 10 days.
你工作十天。
But if it's hourly, you say you'll get paid $10 per hour.
但如果是按小时，你会说每小时付十美元。
So if you work four hours today, you will earn $40.
所以如果你今天工作四小时，你会挣四十美元。
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
So now we want to pay the cleaning lady hourly, but we don't know what the going rate is.
现在我们想按小时付给清洁女工，但我们不知道“going rate”（现行行情）是多少。
Going rate.
现行行情。
Going.
现行。
So this is an interesting phrase and it's important to notice that it's not going rate
所以这是一个有趣的短语，重要的是要注意到“going rate”不是
is an amount of money, but it's not always the same.
一个固定的金额，它并不总是一样的。
Right.
对。
It depends on the industry.
这取决于行业。
So the going rate for a teacher is different from the going rate for a cleaning lady,
所以老师的“going rate”不同于清洁女工的“going rate”，
which is different from the going rate for a language tutor.
也不同于语言辅导老师的“going rate”。
Right.
对。
Or like an English tutor.
或者像英语辅导老师。
So first of all, the going rate is how much these people, these cleaning ladies normally
首先，“going rate”是指这些人，这些清洁女工通常
earn.
挣多少钱。
It's an average.
它是一个平均值。
Right.
对。
So you would usually calculate it, say the approximate going rate is between maybe $8
所以你通常会估算一下，说大概的“going rate”可能在
to $10 per hour.
每小时八到十美元之间。
So it's not like an exact amount.
所以它不是一个精确的金额。
You would say the going rate is more or less a certain amount.
你会说“going rate”大致是某个数额。
It's not exact.
它不精确。
So you might ask your friends, what do you pay your cleaning lady?
所以你可能会问朋友：你付给清洁女工多少钱？
And one friend says, oh, I pay $12 per hour.
一个朋友说，哦，我每小时付十二美元。
And my other friend says, oh, I pay about $8 per hour.
另一个朋友说，哦，我付大约每小时八美元。
So to me, it sounds like the going rate is about $10 per hour.
所以对我来说，听起来“going rate”大约是每小时十美元。
Right.
对。
Exactly.
完全正确。
So we're not really sure what the going rate is.
所以我们不太确定“going rate”是多少。
So our friend says, well, you know what?
所以我们的朋友说，嗯，你知道吗？
I'm sure it's more than minimum wage.
我肯定它比“minimum wage”（最低工资）高。
Now minimum wage is actually something that the government decides on or either the federal
“minimum wage”实际上是政府决定的，要么是美国联邦政府，
government in America or the state.
要么是州政府。
And each state will have a number that they say that is the least you can pay a person
每个州都会有一个数字，规定你每小时至少能付给一个人
per hour.
多少钱。
Right.
对。
So it is the law.
所以这是法律。
If you pay less, it's illegal.
如果你付得更少，那就是违法的。
And this is because we expect everyone to be treated fairly.
这是因为我们期望每个人都能得到公平对待。
Right.
对。
So it's not an advantage of people.
所以这不是对某些人的优势。
No.
不是。
And so, for example, in America, in my state, Illinois, I think the minimum wage is $7.25
所以，举个例子，在美国，我所在的州，伊利诺伊州，我认为最低工资是7.25美元
per hour.
每小时。
Oh, really?
哦，真的吗？
Wow.
哇。
It's pretty high.
这挺高的。
And this is because people need to pay for health care and cars and houses and children.
这是因为人们需要支付医疗、汽车、房子和孩子的费用。
So we say the least you can pay someone is $7.25.
所以我们说，你能付给别人的最低工资是7.25美元。
Now this is different.
这就不一样了。
As you said, it could be different from state to state.
就像你说的，各州可能不同。
Right.
对。
Because I know in some states, if I'm not mistaken, it's like $5.50 or something.
因为我知道有些州，如果我没记错的话，大概是5.50美元左右。
Yeah, some states it's $5.
是啊，有些州是5美元。
It depends on the cost of living.
这取决于生活成本。
If it's cheap to rent an apartment or to find transportation, then obviously the minimum
如果租房或交通便宜，那么显然最低
wage is going to be lower.
工资就会更低。
Obviously there's no maximum wage.
显然没有最高工资。
There's no number that is the most you can pay someone.
没有规定你能付给别人的最高金额。
But all states have a minimum wage.
但所有州都有最低工资。
It's the least that you can pay someone per hour.
这是你每小时能付给别人的最低金额。
Okay.
好的。
So for our last phrase, we don't know what the minimum wage is, we're not really sure
所以对于我们的最后一个短语，我们不知道最低工资是多少，我们不太确定
what the going rate is.
现行行情是多少。
So we should just negotiate with the person that answers the ad.
所以我们应该和回应广告的人协商。
All right.
好的。
Now to negotiate is a great verb.
现在，“协商”是一个很棒的动词。
It is something that all of us do all the time.
这是我们所有人经常做的事情。
So to negotiate means to try and compromise or to reach an agreement.
所以“协商”的意思是试图妥协或达成协议。
So maybe I say the most I will pay is $11.
所以也许我说我最多付11美元。
So I say, okay, I'll pay you $9.
所以我说，好吧，我付你9美元。
And I say, no, I'll take 12.
然后我说，不，我要12美元。
Yeah, sorry, 12 is too much.
是啊，抱歉，12美元太多了。
I'll pay you 10.
我付你10美元。
Okay, 11.
好吧，11美元。
11?
11美元？
Okay, agreed.
好的，成交。
Okay.
好的。
So it's a way of reaching an agreement, like you say, where both sides have their goals
所以这是一种达成协议的方式，就像你说的，双方都有自己的目标
and they try to find a price that is the best for both parties.
他们试图找到一个对双方都最有利的价格。
That's right.
没错。
So it's basically a verb to negotiate and this is what you do, as you said, in many
所以这基本上是一个动词“协商”，正如你所说，你在很多
circumstances, especially when you're getting a job.
情况下都会这样做，尤其是在找工作时。
Yes.
是的。
All right.
好的。
So let's listen to the dialogue one last time and we'll be back in a bit.
那么让我们最后再听一遍对话，我们一会儿回来。
Can you help me write a newspaper ad?
你能帮我写一则报纸广告吗？
Sure.
当然。
What are you looking to buy or sell?
你想买或卖什么？
Actually, I want to hire someone to help me around the house.
实际上，我想雇个人帮我做家务。
Oh, you want to get a maid?
哦，你想找个女佣？
Well, I think it's better if you call her a cleaning lady or domestic help.
嗯，我觉得你最好称她为清洁工或家政帮手。
Okay.
好的。
So what do you want her to do?
那么你想让她做什么？
Well, let's see.
嗯，让我想想。
I want her to come in three times a week for a couple of hours to clean the kitchen, bathroom,
我想让她每周来三次，每次几个小时，打扫厨房、浴室，
and maybe do some cooking.
也许再做点饭。
Got it.
明白了。
And how much do you offer per month?
那你每月付多少钱？
I would pay her hourly.
我会按小时付钱。
I don't know what the going rate is, though.
不过我不知道现行行情是多少。
I know for sure it's more than minimum wage, but maybe you should just negotiate with the
我肯定这比最低工资高，但也许你应该和回应
person that answers the ad.
广告的人协商一下。
Great.
太好了。
I'll be happy to help.
我很乐意帮忙。
All right.
好的。
So talking about minimum wage, is there any exception to why a person would earn less
那么说到最低工资，有没有什么例外情况，让人挣得
than minimum wage?
比最低工资少？
I don't believe so.
我不这么认为。
Well, if they're not legally employed, right?
嗯，如果他们不是合法雇佣的，对吧？
So if you're talking about people who we say are under the table, working under the table,
所以如果你说的是那些我们称为“打黑工”的人，也就是非法工作，
that means that they're not working legally.
那就意味着他们不是合法工作。
They're not paying taxes.
他们不交税。
Then maybe those people will be paid less.
那么那些人可能拿到的工资会更低。
What about waiters and waitresses?
那服务员和女服务员呢？
I've heard that they earn less than minimum wage, but because they earn tips.
我听说他们挣得比最低工资少，因为他们有小费。
This is true.
这是真的。
So most restaurants say, okay, we will pay you as a waiter $3 an hour, but because you
所以大多数餐厅会说，好吧，我们作为雇主每小时付你3美元，但因为你
will earn tips, you will earn more than the minimum wage.
会赚到小费，所以你的收入会高于最低工资。
Right.
没错。
So this is a good exception.
所以这是一个不错的例外情况。
Unfortunately, there's no promise.
不幸的是，这没有保证。
If you have no customers, you earn no tips, so you're still earning less than minimum
如果没有顾客，你就赚不到小费，那么你的收入仍然低于最低
wage.
工资。
That's right.
对。
But if you have many, many customers and you earn lots of tips and you make $15 an hour
但如果顾客很多，你赚了很多小费，每小时能赚15美元
or something much higher than the minimum wage.
或者比最低工资高得多。
That's right.
没错。
And actually being a waiter or a waitress is a very common job that a lot of people
实际上，当服务员是一份很常见的工作，很多人
have when they're still in school or over the summer.
在上学或暑假期间都会做。
And I've heard that it could be quite good because Americans are pretty good tippers.
我听说这工作还不错，因为美国人给小费挺大方的。
That's right.
对。
Americans generally tip between 15 and 20%.
美国人通常给15%到20%的小费。
And you know that you have to tip because your waiter does not earn a minimum wage.
而且你知道必须给小费，因为服务员赚不到最低工资。
Right.
没错。
And so I think there is this expectation.
所以我觉得这是一种约定俗成的期望。
So if your bill comes out to like a hundred bucks, then you are most definitely going
所以如果你的账单是100美元左右，那你肯定得
to leave at least a $20 tip.
留下至少20美元的小费。
Usually, yeah, 15 to $20, $20 if it's that much money.
通常是的，15到20美元，如果账单那么多的话就给20美元。
Wow.
哇。
That's very, very interesting, especially considering that in many countries, tipping
这非常非常有趣，尤其是考虑到在很多国家，小费
is not really considered, it's not expected or it's not really something that people do.
并不被真正考虑，不是预期行为，也不是人们常做的事。
Exactly.
确实如此。
And in America, it is something that you have to do.
而在美国，这是你必须做的事。
So I think a lot of times when people come to America, they don't expect to pay this.
所以我觉得很多时候，人们来美国时，没预料到要付这笔钱。
There's tax, there's tip.
有税，还有小费。
So when you see a menu, remember that the cost is a lot higher than you see.
所以当你看到菜单时，记住实际花费比你看到的要高得多。
Exactly.
没错。
All right.
好了。
Very, very interesting topic.
非常非常有趣的话题。
Let us know if you have any questions, any doubts or comments.
如果你有任何问题、疑问或评论，请告诉我们。
You can find us at EnglishPod.com.
你可以在EnglishPod.com找到我们。
We'll see you guys there.
我们那里见。
Bye.
再见。